歌洛莉亚  亲爱的
Gloria, honey!
我随时都能出发
I'm ready whenever you are!
我们得快点了  预定时间是七点
We should hurry. The reservation's at 7:00.
克莱尔  你在哪儿
Claire, where are you?
好  两分钟后见
Okay, see you in two.
你在干什么呢
What are you doing?
我想摆个性感僚人的姿势给你妈看
I'm striking a seductive pose for your mother.
真恶  不过我喜欢这套西装  新的吗
Gross. But I like the suit. Is that new?
是啊
Oh, yeah.
爹爹的小心肝都开始挣钱了
Now that his honey gots her own money,
爹爹自然要给自己买套新衣裳  闺女
daddy went and snagged hisself some new threads, girl.
这绝对是你最搞笑的声音
Hands down, your funniest voice.
快让人觉得恶心了
Bordering on the offensive.
你看  我是房地产经纪人
Listen, I'm a realtor,
得与很多家庭打交道
and I work a lot with families,
所以通常我不能表现得太性感
so normally, I dial the sexy back to five,
但克莱尔最近工作非常辛苦
but Claire's been working very hard lately.
所以今晚...
So tonight...
留下来看你们的妈妈
Stick around if you want to see
被我迷得口水直流吧
your mom's tongue fall out of her mouth.
还是算了  除非你想看我把午饭吐出来
Not unless you want to see my lunch fall out of mine.
抱歉我回来晚了
Oh, I'm sorry I am late.
路上实在是太堵了
Traffic was horrible.
看起来有人急需一大杯水啊
Sounds like someone could use a tall drink of water.
是啊  对  水
Yeah, right. Water.
卢克  我是怎么跟你说
Luke, what did I tell you about
坐在椅子上向后仰的
leaning back on that thing?
不知道  是"不许这样"吗
I don't know. "Don't"?
亲爱的  你怎么还在这里
Honey, what are you still doing here?
你应该去照看乔了啊
You're supposed to be babysitting Joe.
是  但我得先载艾丽克斯去照看莉莉
Yeah, but I have to drop off Alex to watch Lily first,
但她还没准备好
and she's still not ready.
她不会是在穿衣打扮什么的吧
She can't be concerned about her looks, right?
-我听得见  -我开玩笑的
- I can hear you! - I'm kidding.
我只是想说
I'm just saying,
如果她还试图打扮就挺可悲的
it'd be sad to think she actually tries.
-又听到了  -开玩笑的啦
- Heard that, too! - It was a joke!
老天  大耳朵真的听得更清楚吗
Man, do big ears actually hear better?
我的天哪  别再说了
Oh, my God, just stop talking.
好了  姑娘们
Okay, girls.
你们该出发啦
It's time for you guys to hit the road.
好了  再见
Okay, bye.
-再见  -拜拜
- Oh, yeah, bye. - Bye.
你为什么不跟她们一起去
Why aren't you going with them?
他想待在家里
He wanted to stay home.
我同意了
I said it was okay.
-他自己吗  -没关系的
- By himself? - It's fine.
如果他能和我一起看《行尸走肉》
If he's old enough to watch "The Walking Dead" with me...
-他还不行  -他就可以
- He's not. - then he's old enough
-一个人待在家里了  -他还不行
- to stay home alone. - He's not.
克莱尔  他不是小孩子了
Claire, he's not a little boy anymore.
我没事
I'm fine.
你听他的声音多么低沉
See how deep his voice is?
你还好吗
Are you okay?!
m 20 0 l 209 0 b 218 0 229 11 229 20 l 229 209 b 229 218 218 228 209 228 l 20 228 b 11 228 0 218 0 209 l 0 20 b 0 11 11 0 20 0
m 115 64 l 115 35 l 171 0 l 177 0 l 133 46 l 143 52 l 179 0 l 184 0 l 159 63 l 229 107 l 229 182 l 145 96 l 135 122 l 207 227 l 137 227 l 115 172 l 115 93 l 126 76 l 115 64 l 104 76 l 115 93 l 115 172 l 93 227 l 23 227 l 95 122 l 84 96 l 0 182 l 0 107 l 70 63 l 45 0 l 50 0 l 87 52 l 97 46 l 52 0 l 59 0 l 115 35
m 71 60 b 71 0 161 0 161 60 b 161 120 71 120 71 60
m 325 0 l 355 0 l 332 47 l 354 47 l 399 136 l 369 136 l 328 53 l 288 136 l 257 136 l 325 0 m 467 0 l 497 0 l 474 47 l 496 47 l 541 136 l 511 136 l 470 53 l 430 136 l 399 136 l 467 0 m 545 1 l 583 1 l 583 14 l 568 14 l 568 19 l 583 19 l 583 30 l 568 30 l 568 34 l 599 34 l 599 30 l 583 30 l 583 19 l 599 19 l 599 14 l 583 14 l 583 1 l 611 1 b 616 1 622 6 622 10 l 622 36 l 652 0 l 678 0 l 644 41 l 622 41 l 622 47 l 596 47 l 597 54 l 625 54 l 625 68 l 541 68 l 541 54 l 572 54 l 571 47 l 545 47 l 545 1 m 583 72 l 583 85 l 569 85 l 569 90 l 598 90 l 598 85 l 583 85 l 583 72 l 611 72 b 615 72 621 78 621 82 l 653 44 l 678 44 l 644 86 l 621 86 l 621 103 l 597 103 l 597 136 l 570 136 l 564 126 l 562 136 l 542 136 l 548 107 l 568 107 l 565 121 l 571 121 l 571 103 l 547 103 l 547 72 l 583 72 m 600 107 l 620 107 l 624 124 l 653 89 l 679 89 l 642 136 l 615 136 l 618 132 l 606 132 l 600 107 m 689 0 l 716 0 l 721 15 l 732 15 l 732 30 l 718 56 l 731 56 l 735 100 l 721 100 l 717 59 l 714 64 l 714 136 l 693 136 l 693 79 l 676 79 l 707 30 l 679 30 l 679 15 l 694 15 l 689 0 m 738 0 l 804 0 b 807 0 813 6 813 9 l 813 87 l 794 87 l 794 14 l 756 14 l 756 87 l 763 77 l 763 21 l 787 21 l 787 91 l 798 91 l 798 120 l 820 120 l 812 136 l 778 136 l 778 90 l 748 136 l 723 136 l 756 87 l 738 87 l 738 0 m 257 151 l 275 151 l 297 182 l 319 151 l 337 151 l 304 197 l 304 227 l 290 227 l 290 197 l 257 151 m 337 151 l 355 151 l 377 182 l 399 151 l 417 151 l 384 197 l 384 227 l 370 227 l 370 197 l 337 151 m 425 192 l 447 192 b 445 181 427 181 425 192 l 410 192 b 414 162 458 162 462 192 l 462 206 l 425 206 b 425 210 429 212 433 213 l 462 213 l 462 227 l 433 227 b 412 227 408 203 410 192 m 462 151 l 532 151 l 532 165 l 504 165 l 504 227 l 489 227 l 489 165 l 462 165 l 462 151 m 580 172 l 580 186 l 549 186 b 543 186 543 192 549 192 l 565 192 b 589 192 589 227 565 227 l 532 227 l 532 213 l 565 213 b 570 213 570 206 565 206 l 549 206 b 524 206 524 172 549 172 l 580 172 m 592 213 l 606 213 l 606 227 l 592 227 l 592 213 m 639 172 l 665 172 l 665 186 l 639 186 b 623 186 623 213 639 213 l 665 213 l 665 227 l 639 227 b 603 227 603 172 639 172 m 700 184 b 722 184 722 215 700 215 l 700 229 b 740 229 740 170 700 170 b 660 170 660 229 700 229 l 700 215 b 680 215 680 184 700 184 m 737 172 l 782 172 b 803 172 813 177 813 198 l 813 228 l 799 228 l 799 198 b 799 186 793 187 782 187 l 782 228 l 768 228 l 768 187 l 752 187 l 752 228 l 737 228 l 737 172
人人影视
YYeTs.com
原创翻译  双语字幕
■
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新
请登陆www.YYeTs.com
翻译：小饭  冰蓝  慕秋雪 二千  小牛仔裤  王大可
时间轴：加森    校对：olivia_xuxu   后期&总监：瓜瓜
摩  登
家  庭
第五季 第五集
是海莉的短信
Oh, this is Haley.
"五点到  艾丽克斯特么磨蹭死了"
"Be there in 5. Alex took ducking forever."
没关系  你知道吗
Oh, it's fine. You know what?
我们得选一张"预留时间"卡片
We have to pick the "Save the date" card.
我好纠结
I'm at a loss.
我们能明天再选吗
Can we just do it tomorrow?
我讨厌我们迟到时我爸看我们的眼神
I hate the way my dad looks at us when we're late,
就好像我们是两个傻基佬
like we're two silly queens
一边听迪斯科音乐
blasting disco music,
一边梳洗打扮  毫无时间观念
primping, losing track of time.
你这小脑瓜想象力真丰富
Wow, it gets really busy in that head, huh?
快点  你喜欢哪一张
Okay, quick. Which one do you like?
-那张  -真的吗
- Uh, that one. - Really?
我觉得你太草率了
I think you picked too quick.
不  没有  我真的很喜欢那张
No, I didn't. I really like that one.
我真的很喜欢这张
I really like this one.
那你特么为什么还要问我
Well, then, why did you ducking ask me?
好吧  听你的
Fine, goes with yours.
如果你真喜欢的话  就听你的
Well, if that's the one you really like.
你能快点准备好吗
Can you just get ready?
行  莉莉  开始
Yeah. Lily, hit it.
遵命
On it!
快点  快点走啊  快点
Let's go! Let's go! Let's go!
我从没见你这么迫不及待要去一家餐厅
I've never seen you so excited about a restaurant.
这次预定我已经等了六周了
I've waited six weeks for this reservation.
那家餐厅有澳大利亚神户牛肉
They have an Australian Wagyu beef
简直会颠覆你的人生
that's supposed to change your life.
通过心脏病颠覆你的人生吗
In the way heart disease changes your life?
你真是健康的使者
Because you're a pillar of health.
这种牛只吃苜蓿  大麦和红酒
They only feed this cow alfalfa, barley, and red wine,
每块肉都经过厨师手工挑选
and some chef hand-picks each cut,
然后风干35天
dry ages it 35 days
才做成一道完美的三分熟牛排
before cooking it to a perfect medium-rare,
一切都是为我而做
all for me.
牛喝酒不会醉吗
Doesn't the wine make the cow drunk?
这不是在漫画里  牛又不用开车去哪里
It's not "The Far Dide." The cow doesn't drive anywhere.
歌洛莉亚
Gloria!
快点走了
Let's go!
你知道她不在这里吧
You know she's not here, right?
什么
What?
她在外面吹头发呢
She's having her hair blown out.
就这么个事儿
That's a thing?
要花钱去做吗
That I pay for?
歌洛莉亚总是迟到
Gloria's always late.
然后我就会生气  让她动作快点
Then I get mad and tell her to hurry.
我们会争吵  结果耽误了更多时间
We yell, and it just takes longer.
所以我暗中发誓  无论她多慢
So I promised myself, no matter how late she is,
我就深呼吸几下  保持镇定
just to take some deep breaths and stay calm.
这是我在无痛分娩课上学到的唯一一点
That's the only thing I learned in lamaze class
因为我们那时也总是迟到
because we were always late.
今天晚上大家都跟疯子似的
Hi! Everybody's running like crazy tonight.
我走了圣维森特路  以为会节省时间
I took San Vicente thinking that I was gonna save some time,
结果那里在修下水道
but then they're working on the sewer.
所以我绕道蒙大纳路
So I went around Montana,
又开到莫雷诺路上
down Moreno.
但是那条路上有个坑
But then there's that dip in the road.
我总是忘记路上有个坑
I always forget about that dip in the road.
车颠得太厉害  我把咖啡洒得到处都是
I hit it so hard that I spilled the coffee all over the car.
我跟你说我和谁去喝咖啡了吗
Did I tell you who I had coffee with?
我觉得卢克害怕被单独留在家里
I think Luke is scared to be left in the house alone,
他只是为了你表现得勇敢
and he's just pretending to be brave for you.
亲爱的  他都14岁了
Honey, he's 14.
艾丽克斯10岁时我们就让她一人在家了
We left Alex alone when she was 10.
不是"让"  而是把她忘在家里了
We didn't leave her. We forgot her.
我们赶回家时她不是好好的吗
And when we got home, she was fine.
身体上没事
Physically.
而且她和那个可爱的911接线员
Plus, she's still friends with
现在还是好朋友呢
that sweet 911 operator.
是啊
Yeah.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
确保卢克知道
Making sure Luke knows
发生意外时该怎么做
what to do in case of emergency.
他当然知道
Of course he does.
有人按门铃
Someone's at the door!
卢克  这是你妈妈在测试你
Luke, it's just your mom testing you.
别担心  妈
Don't worry, mom.
你们不在时如果我听到这声音
If I hear that while you're gone,
我不会开门的
I won't answer.
我就躲在没人能找到的地方
I'll just hide where no one can find me.
小卡  我们快走吧
Cam, come on, let's go.
再等两秒钟
Two seconds.
我还以为和男人在一起
I thought that being with a man
意味着我不必这样苦苦等待
meant that I wouldn't have to wait around like this.
我觉得受到了欺骗  真的
I feel cheated. I do.
我们来玩洋娃娃吧
Let's play dolls.
其实  我想给你读我最爱的一本书
Actually, I want to read you one of my favorite books.
书名是《小妇人》  讲的是四姐妹
It's called "Little Women," and it's about four sisters
克服贫困和父权制的故事...
who overcome poverty and the patriarchy...
不听  玩娃娃
Nope! Dolls.
这是阿什莉  她是个家庭主妇
This is Ashley. She's a wife.
希望她不只是个家庭主妇而已
Well, I hope that's not the only thing that defines her.
她有事业吗
Does she have a career?
不  她只购物  海莉在哪
Nope, she shops. Where's Haley?
我怎么五分钟就准备好了
How come it takes me five minutes to get ready,
而你还在磨磨蹭蹭呢
and you take forever?
拜托  我也能在五分钟内准备好
Oh, please. I could get ready in five minutes, too,
如果我穿得像...
if I dressed like --
你们又撞衫了
You did it again.
誓死不换
Not changing.
系好安全带
Fasten your seatbelts.
这会是个疯狂的夜晚
It's going to be a crazy night.
不  亲爱的  这会是个不太平的夜晚
No, honey, it's gonna be a bumpy night.
记住  你有两个爸爸
Remember, you can't have two dads
不能犯这种错误
and make that mistake.
不太平的夜晚
Bumpy night.
好吧  这种事多久发生一次
Okay, so how often does this happen?
太频繁
Too often.
男人没有太多选择
Men just don't have that many options.
简直数不清有多少次
I can't tell you the number of times
我经过女士服装店时
I've walked by a women's boutique
心里想"我愿付出一切
and just thought, "What I would do
来换取那么多的选择"
to have that many choices."
永远别这样说了
Don't ever say that again.
我一点也不喜欢
I don't like any part of it.
好吧  必须得有个人去换衣服
All right, one of us has to change.
我们看起来像教堂里的双胞胎小孩
We look like twin toddlers at church.
谁说不是啊
Yeah, tell me about it.
而且我们要去的地方很高端
And this place we're going is supposed to be super hip.
说不定会碰到熟人
We're probably gonna run into someone.
拜托  我没有你衣服多
And come on. I don't have that many outfits.
我的衣服只占了衣柜的四分之一
My clothes take up exactly one-quarter of the closet.
这样说可不公平  我的衣服比你大
That's not fair. My clothes are bigger than yours.
好吧  我不想打这张牌
All right, I hate to play this card,
但我先换好衣服的  所以
but I was dressed first. So...
真愚蠢
Oh, that is silly.
莉莉  该玩"谁穿上更好看"的游戏了
Lily, it's time to play "Who wore it best?"
不  我不玩了  我做不到
No, I'm not doing this again. I can't.
好吧  艾丽克斯你来
Fine. Alex.
我不知道
Uh, I don't know.
男士衣服我不太懂
Boys' clothes aren't really my thing.
真的吗
Really?
我不明白
I don't get it.
牛喝了酒难道不会醉吗
Doesn't the wine get the cow drunk?
-谢谢你  -天啊
- Thank you. - Honest to God.
你俩都没见过牛吗
Have neither of you seen a cow?
它们体型庞大
They're huge.
我敢说龙舌兰酒会让它们醉得更快
I bet tequila would do it quicker.
目的不是为了让牛喝醉
It's not the goal to get the cow drunk.
没搞错吧
You got to be kidding me.
曼尼  去看看你妈怎么磨蹭那么久
Manny, see why your mother's taking so long.
别告诉她是我让你去的
And don't tell her I sent you.
妈  快点
Mom! Hurry!
别吼啊  我自己也能吼
Don't yell. I could have yelled.
-那你为什么不吼  -因为我不想吼
- Then why didn't you? - Because I didn't want to yell.
-我想让你过去  -你为什么不去
- I want you to go. - Why can't you go?
你怎么就不能乖乖听话呢
Why can't you do what I ask?
我在努力使用新方法
I'm trying to do something new here!
别吼了  杰  我准备好了
Stop yelling, Jay! I'm ready!
天啊
Oh, geez.
海莉  曼尼知道婴儿用的东西放在哪里
Haley, Manny knows where all the baby stuff is,
如果乔不肯睡觉
and if Joe won't go to bed,
就给他放格拉迪斯・奈特的歌曲
just put on Gladys Knight
然后轻轻摇晃他
and bounce him around a little bit.
你还这样做吗
Oh, you still do that?
我以前就很喜欢你摇晃我们
I loved when you did that with us.
怎么样
How about that?
这家里还有人记得我做过的好事
Somebody in this family remembers a nice thing I did.
我记得你做过的好事
I remember something nice you did.
你昨天上班时给我买了这条裙子
You bought me this dress yesterday when you were working.
我看起来怎么样
How do I look?
美极了  我们走吧
Gorgeous. Let's go!
你都没看我  海莉
You didn't even look at me. Haley.
首先  你的发型看起来棒极了
Well, "A," your hair looks amazing,
就像是刚从马背上下来似的
like you just got off a horse.
那正是我想要的效果
That's exactly what I was going for.
不过我觉得吧...
But if I had one thought...
别  别觉得
No! No thoughts.
那对耳环不是最适合的
...are those for sure the best earrings?
感觉不是很显眼
They seem to be kind of getting lost.
我还有一副这个颜色大一号的
I have the same color in a bigger size.
-大多少  -一米左右
- How much bigger? - Like a meter.
一米都有一英尺长了
A meter? That's like a foot.
其实应该是一码才对
Actually, it's like a yard.
对不起  应该是一毫米左右
Oh, sorry -- it's like a millimeter.
你想说的是一厘米吧
You mean a centimeter.
数学真麻烦  给我看一下好了
All this math. Just show me.
-歌洛莉亚  -怎么的
- Gloria! - What?
我觉得那副新耳环
I think the new earrings
一定会和你的整套造型非常搭
are really gonna tie your whole outfit together.
你嘴真甜
You're so sweet!
你刚才的表现成熟多了
Wow. That was very mature of you.
是啊  我现在的确比
Yeah, well, I'm a lot older now
她开始打扮之前老多了
than when she started getting dressed.
所以这个声音
So this sound...
才是门铃声
...that's the doorbell.
之前那个声音是烟雾报警器
That other sound was the smoke alarm.
知道了
Got it.
如果你饿了  不要叫批萨外卖
Okay, and if you're hungry, don't order a pizza.
他们的配送员都没有经过筛选
They don't screen those delivery guys.
那些人多半都是有前科的
Half of them are ex-cons.
够了  你会吓到他的  不会有事的
Stop it. You're gonna scare him. It's gonna be fine.
不过万一你噎住了  你要这样
But if you do choke, you've gotta throw yourself
撞在椅子背上以便把食物吐出来
against the back of a chair to get the food out.
他喝点东西就行了
He'll just drink stuff.
不要拿水槽下面的东西喝
Nothing from under the sink.
连柠檬味的也不行吗
Even if it's lemony?
我跟你开玩笑的
I'm just messing with you.
要是着火  就俯下身子跑出去
In case of fire, go low and get out.
要是遇到地震
In case of earthquake --
等一下  你们觉得会发生地震吗
Wait. You think there could be an earthquake?
上次地震时  我被那个大柜子压住了
The last time we had one, that big cabinet fell on me.
-没有的事  -真的吗
- No, it didn't. - It did?!
我们走吧
Let's go.
再见  亲爱的  我们爱你
Bye, honey, we love you.
你有钥匙没
Do you have the keys?
我们会给你打电话的  我保证
We're gonna check in. I promise!
怎么回事
Uhh, what's going on?
新西服
New suit?
这个吗
This old thing?
是啊  是新的
Yes, it is.
我在市里潮人集散地买的
I got it at this hipster place downtown.
你喜欢吗
You like it?
有点儿紧
It's tight.
售货员说现在流行这种风格
Well, the salesman said it was the style,
他看上去像个蒙福之子乐队成员
and he looked like a Mumford and Son,
我以为他很了解时尚
so I think he'd know.
我们走吧
Mm, let's go.
慢一点  女飞人
Slow down, Flo Jo.
我们没有时间争论这些了
You know what? We don't have time for this.
我直接换衣服好了
I'll just change.
这让我好内疚  我们还是一起换了吧
Well, now I feel bad. Let's both just change.
这样做才公平
That's the fair thing to do.
好的  但是请你快一点
Okay, fine. But quickly, pLemony Snicketlease.
我不知道
I don't know.
这件是蓝色的
It's blue.
这件又太黄了
Yeah, this one's so yellow.
你猜怎么着
Oh, you know what?
这件衣服上有块污渍  我不能穿这件
I have a stain on this one. I can't wear it.
涡纹图案  不错  我不确定
Oh, paisley, yeah. I don't know.
你是在跟我开玩笑吗
Are you kidding me right now?!
-怎么了  -我知道你在耍什么把戏
- What? - I know this trick, Cam.
你永远也挑不出一套衣服
You take forever to pick out an outfit,
你知道我肯定会说"我们走吧"
knowing very well that I'll say, "Let's just go,"
因为我们已经迟了
because we're late.
这么一来  你做了提议换装的好人
Meantime, you get credit for offering to change
而我却是真正换装的那个人
while I'm the one who actually does.
-你一向如此  -你说什么
- As usual. - Excuse me.
你是在指责我操纵你按我的方式做事吗
Are you accusing me of manipulating you to get my way?
其实...
Actually...
因为我妈以前就是那么指责我的
Because that's what my mother used to accuse me of,
我不得不说
and I got to say
那让我想起了好多伤心事
that that brings up a lot of stuff with me.
你连滴眼泪都挤不出来
You're crying without tears.
给我点时间
Give me a minute.
"圣诞节要是没有礼物就不是圣诞节了"
"'Christmas won't be Christmas without any presents,'
"乔抱怨道"
"Grumbled Jo.
"贫困真是可怕  她感叹着"
'it's so dreadful to be poor,' sighed --"
够了  我不爱听这个
Stop! I hate this.
我能给你化妆吗
Can I put makeup on you?
怎么总有人这么问我
Why does everyone ask me that?
我们今晚就高高兴兴地享受一下行吗
Let's just have a good time tonight, all right?
-我没生气  -好  很好
- I'm not mad. - Okay, good.
而且你穿那套衣服帅呆酷毙了
And you do look super-duper handsome in that.
别扯了
Don't even.
我去拿些水在路上喝
I'm gonna grab a water for the road.
给我拿罐汽水
Yeah, get me a soda.
好了  艾丽克斯  非常感谢你
Okay, Alex. Thank you so much.
晚上玩得开心点
Have a fun night.
宝贝  我们爱你
Honey, we love you.
-给你  -好的  谢谢
- Here you go. -All right. Thank you.
记住  不许在客厅里吃东西
Okay, and remember, no eating in the living room.
我的天  我的天
Aah! Oh, my god! Oh, my god!
你做了什么  你做了什么
What did you do? What did you do?!
拜托  你不会以为...
Come on! You can't possibly think --
你摇晃这罐子来着
You shook this can
这样你就能穿这套我想穿的衣服了
so you could wear the outfit that I wanted to wear?
是的  我就是这么想的
That is exactly what I think!
这太荒谬了
That is insane.
你看着我把汽水从冰箱里
You saw me take it from the refrigerator
-拿出来给你的  -是吗
- and bring it to you. - Did I?
还是你趁我没注意
Or were you out of my sight for the two seconds
在从冰箱那里走过来的两秒钟里
that it took you to get from the refrigerator to here,
摇晃了这罐汽水  而两秒钟刚好足够
which would have given you exactly the right amount of time
用来摇晃汽水
to shake the can?
真棒  大神探  但我没那么小心眼
Nice theory, Nancy Grace, but I'm not that petty.
你们俩看见什么没有
Okay, you two. Did you see anything?
假装在涂色
Just pretend you're coloring.
你在干嘛
Okay, what are you doing?
我在尝试够到镜子
I'm trying to reach the mirror.
我眼睛里进东西了
I got something in my eye.
你好  这里是邓菲家
Hi, you've reached the Dunphys.
卢克为什么不接电话
Why isn't Luke picking up?
被一个刚被假释的
It's hard to reach the phone
比萨配送员绑住  的确很难接电话
when you're tied up by a recently paroled pizza guy.
你真幽默
Ha ha. You're very funny.
你干什么
What are you doing?
我知道这听起来很奇怪
I know it sounds weird.
也许是母亲的直觉吧
Call it mother's intuition,
但我有种不祥的预感
but I just have this feeling that something is wrong.
好吧  你爱怎样就怎样吧
Fine, do what you want,
但我已经忍了你...
but I've just about had it up to --
比这还要多
higher than here with this.
去死吧  送比萨的
Die, pizza man!
住手  住手
Stop! Stop!
妈妈啊  对不起
Oh. Sorry, mom.
告诉过你他能照顾好自己了
Told you he could take care of himself.
让开
Move.
她为什么要这样呢
Why does she do this?
我们的订位会被取消的
We're gonna lose our table.
她知道准时到达对我有多重要
She knows how important it is to me to be on time.
真是折磨人
This is torture.
你重点搞错了吧  杰
I think you've lost perspective, Jay.
你知道我愿付出多少来换取
You know what I would give to wait around
等待这样一个女人的权利吗
for a woman like that?
少来了  小变态
Reel it in, creepy.
你说的可是你亲娘
That's your mother up there.
抱歉  抱歉
Sorry, sorry.
我换了耳环之后  就得把鞋子也换了
Once I changed the earrings, I had to change the shoes.
然后我试穿了歌洛莉亚的一条裙子
And then I tried on one of Gloria's old dresses,
让我觉得自己像个10岁的小男孩
which made me feel like a 10-year-old boy.
你身材很棒
Ay, your body's beautiful.
我同意
I agree.
留着对外人说去
Take it outside the family.
准备好出发了吗
Okay, we ready to go?
等等  我拿错了口红
Wait. I have the wrong lipstick.
够了  我受够了
Oh! That's it! I've had it!
就给我一分钟
Just one minute!
你不可能一分钟内做完
Nothing takes a minute with you.
我们现在就走
We're leaving right now.
我不管你要干嘛
I don't care what you have to do.
你对我这么无礼也就算了
It's bad enough you're being rude to me,
但你这样对那些
but you're being rude
在等着我们的人太不尊重了
to the people sitting there waiting for us!
不好意思  你们是最先到的
Sorry, you're the first to arrive,
我们必须等到客人来齐后才能让您入座
and we can't seat you till everyone's here.
这下你开心了吧
I hope you're happy!
人都去哪儿了
Where the hell is everybody?
我讨厌这样等着别人
Yes, I hate waiting like this.
是吗
Do you?
就算其他人都迟到了
Just because everybody else is late
并不意味着我们迟到是对的
doesn't make it okay for us to be late.
你总是吼我  我没法快速准备好
I can't get ready fast with all the yelling!
我没有吼你
I wasn't yelling.
你又在吼我了
You see, you're doing it again!
歌洛莉亚  你每次都是这样
Gloria, you do this every single time.
如果你清楚你要花很长时间准备
If you know how long it takes you to get ready,
为什么不早点开始呢
why don't you start earlier?
我有原因
I have my reasons.
能告诉我吗
I would love to know them.
你会嘲笑人家的
You're going to be mean.
我保证我不会
I promise I won't be.
我喜欢华丽地登场
I like to make an entrance.
你说什么
What's that, now?
我喜欢我走进去的时候
I like the part where I go in,
大家都在等我
and everybody's waiting for me,
然后他们说
and they say,
"歌洛莉亚  你看起来好漂亮
"Gloria, you look so pretty,
那裙子好美啊"
and that dress is so beautiful."
这样有什么不好吗
Is that so bad?
我不喜欢
I don't love it.
这里真华丽呀
Oh, this room is so nice.
是啊  华丽得像...你这个禽兽
I know. It's almost as gorgeous as -- you monster!
什么  这个吗
What? Oh, this?
反正你也没法穿
Well, you know, you couldn't wear it,
所以我想  我何不穿呢
so I figured, what's the harm?
好  你知道吗  我现在要走过去
Mm. Okay, you know what? I will go over there,
然后我会一如既往地魅力十足
and I will be as socially magnetic as I always am.
我们暂且不提这事
We will put this on the back burner,
但我希望你知道  我内心已经气炸了
but underneath, I want you to know, I am fuming.
杰  歌洛莉亚呢
Hey, Jay, where's Gloria?
她刚刚还在那儿呢
She's -- she was there a second --
我的宝贝儿们来啦
There are my boys!
歌洛莉亚  你真漂亮
Gloria, you look so pretty.
这裙子太美了
That dress is so beautiful.
有没有搞错
You got to be kidding me.
你让他跟你一起看那些恐怖电视剧
You let him watch those scary shows with you,
然后我们大晚上把他一人留在家
and then we leave him home alone at night.
他当然会武装自己了
Of course he's gonna arm himself.
你给他讲"50种死法"前他都挺好的
He was fine until you gave him your "50 Ways to Die" speech.
有关"欢迎到来"地毯的说的是什么来着
What was the one about the welcome mat?
那种地毯非常易燃
They are highly flammable.
每年有7到10人死于地毯自燃
For seven to ten people a year,
毯子上不如写"欢迎来停尸房"好了
they may as well say, "Welcome to the morgue."
好了  别说了
You know what? Drop it.
我不想在公共场合吵架
I don't want to fight in public.
-太丢人了  -好吧
- It's embarrassing. - Fine.
你好吗
Hi, how are you?
晚上好  我很好
Good evening. Good.
我的腿麻了
Oh, my leg's asleep!
我的腿麻了  好了  谢谢
My leg's asleep! Okay, thank you.
先生  如果您的朋友们还不到
Sir, if the rest of your party doesn't arrive soon,
恐怕就得把桌子让给别人了
we have to give up your table.
马上就到
Any minute.
再次道歉  爸  我们迟到了
Again, dad, sorry we're late.
是啊  米奇尔放了点音乐
Yeah, you know, Mitchell put on some music,
我们边收拾边跳起舞来了
and we were primping and dancing around,
然后可能就忘记了时间
and I guess, well, we just lost track of time.
事实上  爸  真实情况是
Actually, dad, what happened
小卡玩了个把戏
was Cam was practicing this trick
假装善解人意  却神不知鬼不觉地
where he pretends to be accommodating
得到了自己想要的结果
and then magically gets his way.
他们来了
There they are.
我们要离开一下
We need a second.
小卡  别
Oh, Cam, no.
你们要去哪
Where are you guys going?
我不想说话  太生气了
Can't talk. Too mad.
天哪
Oh, God.
爸
Hi, dad.
歌洛莉亚在哪里
Where's Gloria?
她  看在老天爷的份上
She -- for the love of --
你们来了
There you are!
我的天啊  这裙子
Oh, my goodness! That dress!
歌洛莉亚  好家伙
Gloria, holy mackerel.
真抱歉  我们迟到了
We're so sorry we're late.
我们不得不把卢克送到你们家
We had to drop Luke off at your place.
菲尔想让他自己呆在家  但他害怕
Phil wanted him to stay home alone, but he got scared.
老天  真想赶紧吃点东西
Man, I can't wait to get some food
用食物堵住你的嘴
in my mouth and yours.
可怜的海莉
Poor Haley.
她带着那些男孩子要怎么办啊
What is she going to do with all those boys?
我会陪着他*
*I'll be with him
我料到你会*
*I know you will
搭午夜的火车去往乔治亚*
*On that midnight train to Georgia
搭午夜去往乔治亚的火车离去*
*Leaving on the midnight train to Georgia
你知道么
You know what?
我很讨厌你觉得我每次都得偿所愿
I resent the implication that I always get my way.
真的吗  "预留时间"卡片
Really? The "Save the date" cards.
为我们婚礼准备的那个吗
For our wedding?
那还是"我们"的婚礼啊
Oh. So, it is still our wedding.
我都不确定我是否被邀请了
I wasn't sure I was even invited
因为尽管你一直问我的意见
because you keep asking for my opinion
最后却总是按自己的意愿去做
and then doing the exact opposite.
-那只是特例  -那音乐呢
- That's one thing. - What about the music?
我们的爱值得乐队来衬托  而不是DJ
I think our love deserves a band, not a D.J.
那桌布呢
The tablecloths.
那种料子结实到可以用来做球鞋
They make sneakers out of that fabric.
你什么都不让我选  你想知道为什么吗
You won't let me pick one thing, and you want to know why?
因为我的品味比你好
Because I have better taste than you.
我想说的是因为你是个控制狂
I was gonna say because you're a control freak.
你怎么能认为我品味不好呢
And how can you think that I have bad taste?
我们今天选了一模一样的装扮
We chose the exact same outfit.
真的吗
Did we?
我穿了轻松的懒汉鞋
I wore fun loafers.
你穿了实用的牛津鞋
You wore sensible oxfords.
你的领口系的紧
Your collar's buttoned down.
我的是时下流行的敞开状
Mine's a more current widespread.
我选了一条醒目的方巾
And I chose a bold pocket square
去衬托衬衫的条纹
to bring out the stripe in the shirt,
所有这些都是你想不到的
all of which you wouldn't have thought of.
原因呢  我刚刚已经说过了
Because, well, I've already said.
你不喜欢我的牛津鞋吗
You don't like my oxfords?
对不起  我嘴太毒了
I'm sorry. I'm being harsh.
-他们还说得过去  -谢谢
- They're fine. - Thank you.
如果你是个乡村侦探的话
For a small-town detective.
好吧  我没忍住  我又毒舌了
Okay, look. I can't help myself. I did it again.
我不爱你的鞋
So, I-I don't love them.
但我爱你
But I do love you.
我不想让你感觉被冷落
And I don't want you to feel left out.
好  那让我在婚礼策划中有话语权
Okay. Then let me have a say in planning our wedding.
我们之前说好了的
That's what we agreed to.
你会的  你也应该有  对不起
You will, and you should, and I'm sorry.
谢谢
Thank you.
那你能为我做一件事吗
Can you just do one thing for me?
当然
Sure.
实话回答我  然后我就不会再提
Just be honest, and I'll let this go forever.
你到底有没有摇那罐汽水
Did you shake that can?
没有
No.
我再问一遍
I'm gonna ask you one more time.
看到了吗  菲尔
See, Phil?
他们不让曼尼独自呆在家
They don't let Manny stay home alone.
要不然为什么海莉会在那里
Why do you think Haley's there?
事实上  我们经常让曼尼自己在家
Actually, we let Manny stay home all the time,
有时  他还会做小蛋糕
and sometimes, he makes cupcakes,
现在要是能吃上一个就好了
which I could use one right about now --
或者烤土豆也行
or a potato.
海莉是去照顾乔的
Haley's there to take care of Joe.
你们确定么
Are you sure, guys?
因为克莱尔说的所有事都是对的
'cause Claire's always right about everything
一直以来  永永远远都是对的
all the time, forever and ever.
谢天谢地  他们来了
Thank god. Here they are.
菲奥纳  我们都到了
Fiona, we're all here.
事实上  爸  我们需要点时间
Actually, dad, we could use a moment.
我要吃我的手了
I'm going to eat my hand.
"乔马上坐起来了"
"Jo immediately sat up,
"把手插进了口袋  开始吹口哨"
"put her hands in her pockets, and began to whistle.
"别这样  乔  太像男孩子了"
"Don't, Jo. It's so boyish."
"我就想这样"
"That's why I do it."
"粗鲁的假小子最讨厌了"
"I detest rude, unladylike girls."
"没个性又做作的小孩才讨厌"
"I hate affected, niminy-piminy chits."
好吧  烂透了  我放弃
Okay, this stinks. I give up.
谢天谢地
Thank god.
想看看自己的头发吗
Want to see your hair?
莉莉  还挺好看的呢
Lily, that's actually good.
你真会化妆吗
Can you really do makeup?
好生等着
Stay there.
你在做这么大的决定前该跟我商量下
Is it really too much to ask that you consult me
我这个要求真的很过分吗
before you make such a big decision?
克莱尔  你决定重返职场时
Claire, when you went back to work,
把大权交付给了我
you asked me to take the reins.
那么你现在应当信任我才对
So I think you need to trust me now.
你真觉得我会让儿子陷入险境吗
Do you really think I'd put Luke in a dangerous situation?
我最疼他了  这话你就当没听见
He's my favorite, which I did not just say.
-如果他出点什么岔子  -不会的
- If anything happens to him... - It won't.
你没注意到吗  其实我很擅长处理这些
If you haven't noticed, I'm pretty good at this,
就跟你吝于夸赞我一样
as hard as it is for you to pay me a compliment.
你这话什么意思
Where is that coming from?
那你喜欢这套西服吗
Well, do you like this suit?
我无从知道
I wouldn't know
因为你只说它"有点儿紧"
because all you said was, "It's tight,"
而且还不是开玩笑说的
and not in a cool black way.
等等  你是想说你把自己
Wait, a-are you trying to say
塞进这身西装是为了取悦我吗
that you squeezed yourself in that for me?
是的
Yes.
你最近被工作弄得有些心烦
You've been a little distracted at work,
所以我想为你打扮一下
so I wanted to look nice for you.
亲爱的
Oh, honey.
我不好  是我不好
I'm sorry. I'm so sorry.
你是对的
You're right.
卢克可能本来好好的
Luke probably would have been fine,
是我自己放不下
and I am having a hard time letting go.
如果这世上我只信任一个人  那就是你
And if there's one person in the world I trust, it is you.
还有呢
And?
还有  你穿这套西装真性感
And...you look hot in that suit.
一会儿我们回家...
When we get home later...
行了  千万别往下说了
Okay, you're actually gonna need to stop.
这西服已经紧得不能再紧了
This suit can't get any tighter.
我们回来啦
Hey, we're back.
谁都不许再离开了
Nobody goes anywhere.
大家手拉手  我们赶紧去坐下
Everybody hold hands, and we go right to the table.
菲奥纳
Fiona?
实际上  我们把你们的桌子给别人了
Actually, we just gave away your table.
实在抱歉  但我提醒过你的
I'm sorry, but I did warn you about this.
你给我听着  菲奥莉娜
Listen to me, Fiorina.
这男人为了在你家馆子吃饭
This man has been waiting
已经等了好几个月了
to eat in this restaurant for months!
我们都很自私  害他迟到
We were all selfish, and we made him late.
也许我是有点过分
And maybe I got a little crazy,
但这个等下再考虑
but I'm gonna think about that later.
但他没做错什么
But he has done nothing wrong!
所以在他吃到他天天念叨的
So we're not gonna leave this place
醉牛之前  我们是绝对不会
until he eats that drunk cow
离开这个地方的
that he can't shut up his mouth about!
怎么还傻愣在那
Why you haven't moved?
昨晚我吃到了人生中最美味的一餐
Last night, I had the greatest meal I've ever had,
要不是因为歌洛莉亚让我们
and it never would have happened
被那店大欺客的餐厅赶了出来
if Gloria hadn't got us kicked out
我是没办法享受到的
of that snooty restaurant.
玉米饼
Tacos.
-玉米饼  -我得吃一个
- Tacos. - I need a taco.
-太好了  -玉米饼贩卖车
- Yes. - Taco truck!
太好吃了
That is delicious.
说真的  谁穿得更好看
No, but seriously, who looks better?
也不知道是因为等他们时喝掉的
I don't know if it was the six scotches I drank
六杯苏格兰威士忌作祟
waiting for everybody,
还是因为我早饭之后就没吃过东西
or the fact that I hadn't eaten anything since breakfast...
或是因为菲尔的西服终于撑不住了
or the moment Phil's suit finally gave up.
他们甚至放了我最爱的音乐
They even played my favorite song.
他正离去*
*He's leaving
离去*
*Leaving
搭午夜的火车去往乔治亚*
*On that midnight train to Georgia
搭午夜的火车离去*
*Leaving on the midnight train
说要回去找寻*
*Said he's going back to find
回去找寻*
*Going back to find
那更单纯的地方和时光*
*the simpler place and time
是的  他正离去*
*Oh, yes, he is
我会陪着他*
*And I'll be with him
是的  他要离去*
*Yes, he will
搭午夜的火车去往乔治亚*
*On that midnight train to Georgia
我永远赶不上午夜列车
A train I'd never make
除非我告诉歌洛莉亚火车11点开
unless I told Gloria it left at 11:00.
我宁愿活在他的世界里*
*I'd rather live in his world
也不愿独自过活*
*than live without him in mine
给你
Here you go.
不知道你要喝什么
I didn't know what you wanted to drink,
所以就买了汽水
so I just got you this soda.
可以的  谢谢
That's fine. Thank you.
小卡  你动了什么手脚
Cam, what did you do?
动了跟你一样的手脚
I did exactly what you did
因为我太了解你了
because I know you so well.
我没摇那罐汽水
I didn't shake the soda.
那就没什么可担心的了
Then you have nothing to worry about,
直接打开吧
so go ahead and open it.
我摇了  好吧
I shook it, okay?
我的确摇了  是我摇的
I shook the soda. I shook it up!
满意了吗
Are you happy?
我的行为小心眼  愚蠢还很恶毒
It was petty and stupid and awful.
对不起
I'm sorry.
该死
Damn it.